A Guide to the Department of Education, School Buildings Service, Architectural drawings and plans, 1920-1970
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
A Guide to the Department of Education, School Buildings Service, Architectural drawings and plans, 1920-1970
Library of Virginia
28487
Consists of approximately 3600 sheets of mostly pencil on paper with some blueprints, Diazo prints, photographs, and color renderings.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access to architectural and engineering plans and drawings of current governmental buildings requires a written request from the prospective user and written authorization from the appropriate authority within the agency occupying the facility. See Archives staff for further information.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the Department of Education School Buildings Service, Richmond, Virginia, 19 November 1974.
Alternative Form Available
Most of the original documents in this collection are also available on microfilm (miscellaneous reels 1830-1837). Researchers should note that material in Series III. is not available on film, but the drawings and plans in Series IV. are only available on film. Please see the individual series descriptions for information on specific reel assignments.
Biographical/Historical Information
Originally commissioned to ensure that requirements for light, air, sanitation, and fire safety established in the 1919 Code of Virginia were met, the Division of School Buildings gradually assumed the responsibility of designing or accepting plans for newly consolidated and reformed schools. Though slight modifications to the plans could be made to conform to each region's aesthetic preference, the basic plan, designed to positively affect the educational experience of the students, came from the Division of School Buildings.
As a matter of form, school designs and plans are submitted to The Department of Education's Facilities Management Division today, though the individual localities themselves choose and approve designs for their schools.
Scope and Content
This accession consists of original pencil on tracing paper architectural drawings and plans, renderings and prints for both urban and rural schools in Virginia from 1920-1970. The collection is arranged into three series: Series I. Localities, which consists of drawings for specific schools in those locations; Series II. Renderings/Photographs, which consists of architectural renderings and photographs of school buildings, including the original schools on the particular site, as well as newly constructed schools; Series III. Standard Plans, which consists of standardized plans for various types of school buildings and related structures; and Series IV. Drawings on Microfilm Only, which consists of a variety of school drawings and plans for which the Library of Virginia does not hold the originals.
The majority of these plans were designed by in-house architects, however, some outside professionals were utilized. While most are standard designs, aesthetic additions were made to individual buildings to suit the architectural character of the locality or municipality. Many of the structures represented were new construction undertaken as a result of education reforms in the first half of the 20th century.
Arrangement
Series I. Localities
Series II. Renderings/Photographs
Series III. Standard Plans
Series IV. Drawings on Microfilm Only
Contents List
- Series I. Localities. (Box 1-10., Reel 1832-1837.)
  Contains drawings for specific schools in various Virginia localities.
  Arranged alphabetically by locality.
  Folders 1-L-1 through 3-R-16 can be found on Miscellaneous Reel 1832.
  Folders 3-R-17 through 6-L-10 can be found on Miscellaneous Reel 1833.
  Folders 6-L-11 through 7-R-7 can be found on Miscellaneous Reel 1834.
  Folders 7-R-8 through 9-R-4 can be found on Miscellaneous Reel 1835.
  Folders 9-R-5 through 10-L-17 can be found on Miscellaneous Reel 1836.
  Folders 10-L-18 through 13-L-12 can be found on Miscellaneous Reel 1837, excluding folders 12-L-9 and 12-R-1 which were not filmed.
  - Accomack - Onancock, July 1928 (Folder 1, Folder 1-L-1)
  - Accomack - Bloxam, Feb 1931 (Folder 1, Folder 1-L-2)
  - Accomack - Tangier, March 1932 (Folder 1, Folder 1-L-3)
  - Accomack - Colored Training, March 1933 (Folder 1, Folder 1-L-4)
  - Accomack - Mapsburg, n.d. (Folder 1, Folder 1-L-4)
  - Accomack - Central High School, n.d. (Folder 1, Folder 1-L-5)
  - Accomack - New Church, Feb 1931 (Folder 1, Folder 1-L-5)
  - Albemarle - Broadus Wood, July 1935 (Folder 1, Folder 1-L-9)
  - Albemarle - Red Hill, May 1939 (Folder 1, Folder 1-L-11)
  - Albemarle - Meriwether Lewis, April 1939 (Folder 1, Folder 1-L-11)
  - Albemarle - Stoney Point, July 1935 (Folder 1, Folder 1-L-10)
  - Albemarle - Nine Room School, July 1923 (Folder 1, Folder 1-L-8)
  - Albemarle - Scottsville, May 1923 (Folder 1, Folder 1-L-7)
  - Albemarle - Crozet, Feb 192- (Folder 1, Folder 1-L-6)
  - Albemarle - Greenwood, April 1939 (Folder 1, Folder 1-L-11)
  - Alleghany - Boiling Springs (Pots Creek), May 1927 (Folder 1, Folder 1-L-13)
  - Alleghany - Covington Colored Elementary, Aug 1938 (Folder 1, Folder 1-L-14)
  - Alleghany - Two Room School (Boys Town), July 1933 (Folder 1, Folder 1-L-14)
  - Alleghany - Iron Gate- Addition, May 1935 (Folder 1, Folder 1-L-14)
  - Alleghany - Dunlap, July 1928 (Folder 1, Folder 1-L-15)
  - Alleghany - Dunlap, July 1933 (Folder 1, Folder 1-L-15)
  - Alleghany - Low Moor, Jan 1929 (Folder 1, Folder 1-L-16)
  - Amelia - Amelia Storage Building, June 1939 (Folder 1, Folder 1-L-20)
  - Amelia - Amelia High School- Addition, June 1946 (Folder 1, Folder 1-L-20)
  - Amelia - Rosenwald Revisions, n.d. (Folder 1, Folder 1-L-20)
  - Amelia - Six Room, Feb 1926 (Folder 1, Folder 1-L-18)
  - Amelia - Watson, June 1927 (Folder 1, Folder 1-L-19)
  - Amherst - Madison Heights Elementary, Feb 1939 (Folder 1, Folder 1-L-26)
  - Amherst - Clifford, 1939 (Folder 1, Folder 1-L-27)
  - Amherst - Madison Heights Negro School, Feb 1939 (Folder 1, Folder 1-L-25)
  - Amherst - Temperance High School, May 1938 (Folder 1, Folder 1-L-24)
  - Amherst - Madison Heights High School- Addition, 1937 (Folder 1, Folder 1-L-23)
  - Amherst - Auditorium for Amherst, May 1930 (Folder 1, Folder 1-L-22)
  - Amherst - Madison Heights- Addition, May 1930 (Folder 1, Folder 1-L-21)
  - Amherst - Madison Heights- Heating, July 1927 (Folder 1, Folder 1-L-21)
  - Amherst - Amherst- Toilet Addition, Jan 1926 (Folder 1, Folder 1-L-21)
  - Amherst - Pleasant View- Addition, June 1925 (Folder 1, Folder 1-L-21)
  - Amherst - Madison Heights- Addition, Dec 1933 (Folder 1, Folder 1-L-21)
  - Appomattox - Alterations to Auditorium, July 1931 (Folder 1, Folder 1-R-1)
  - Appomattox - Kitchen Addition, Dec 1940 (Folder 1, Folder 1-R-2)
  - Appomattox - Auditorium & Classrooms, July 1922 (Folder 1, Folder 1-R-1)
  - Appomattox - Agricultural Shop- Addition, April 1943 (Folder 1, Folder 1-R-2)
  - Appomattox - Alterations to Auditorium, July 1931 (Folder 1, Folder 1-R-1)
  - Appomattox - Vocational Building- Addition, April 1943 (Folder 1, Folder 1-R-2)
  - Clarke - Berryville, n.d. (Folder 2, Folder 3-L-20)
  - Clarke - Boyse Elementary, n.d. (Folder 2, Folder 3-L-20)
  - Craig - New Castle, June 1926 (Folder 2, Folder 3-R-1)
  - Craig - Maywood, n.d. (Folder 2, Folder 3-L-19)
  - Craig - Barbers Creek - (Three Room), 1926 (Folder 2, Folder 3-R-1)
  - Culpeper - Culpeper High School- Shop, Feb 1940 (Folder 2, Folder 3-R-3)
  - Culpeper - Mitchels- Addition, June 1937 (Folder 2, Folder 3-R-2)
  - Culpeper - Culpeper County Training, Nov 1935 (Folder 2, Folder 3-R-3)
  - Culpeper - Mitchels, Dec 1933 (Folder 2, Folder 3-R-2)
  - Cumberland - Cartersville- Addition, April 1926 (Folder 2, Folder 3-R-4)
  - Cumberland - Hamilton High School- Heating, Nov 1935 (Folder 2, Folder 3-R-4)
  - Cumberland - Browns Church- Addition, n.d. (Folder 2, Folder 3-R-5)
  - Cumberland - Browns Church- Addition, n.d. (Folder 2, Folder 3-R-5)
  - Cumberland - Cumberland Colored High School, n.d. (Folder 2, Folder 3-R-6)
  - Dickenson - Lyons Fork- Addition, Jan 193- (Folder 2, Folder 3-R-10)
  - Dickenson - West Dante- Addition, Feb 194- (Folder 2, Folder 3-R-10)
  - Dickenson - Sand Lick (Abner Gap) Consolidated, Feb 193- (Folder 2, Folder 3-R-10)
  - Dickenson - Ervinton Elementary, April 193- (Folder 2, Folder 3-R-9)
  - Dickenson - One Room School, April 193- (Folder 2, Folder 3-R-8)
  - Dickenson - Haysi, Aug 1928 (Folder 2, Folder 3-R-7)
  - Dickenson - Turner- Addition, Feb 193- (Folder 2, Folder 3-R-8)
  - Dickenson - Clincho (Folder 2, Folder 3-R-10)
  - Dinwiddie - Sunnyside-McKenny, May 193- (Folder 2, Folder 3-R-12)
  - Dinwiddie - Midway Primary, March 194- (Folder 2, Folder 3-R-14)
  - Dinwiddie - Midway, Sept 193- (Folder 2, Folder 3-R-14)
  - Dinwiddie - Mount Level- Addition, June 194- (Folder 2, Folder 3-R-13)
  - Dinwiddie - Agricultural Shop, June 1938 (Folder 2, Folder 3-R-13)
  - Dinwiddie - Playground Improvement, Aug 1937 (Folder 2, Folder 3-R-13)
  - Dinwiddie - School Bus Garage (Folder 2, Folder 3-R-13)
  - Dinwiddie - Sunnyside-McKenny- Addition, Sept 193- (Folder 2, Folder 3-R-12)
  - Dinwiddie - Carson- Addition, July 193- (Folder 2, Folder 3-R-11)
  - Dinwiddie - Carson, May 192- (Folder 2, Folder 3-R-11)
  - Dinwiddie - Dinwiddie Training, July 193- (Folder 2, Folder 3-R-15)
  - Dinwiddie - Community Recreation Building, Aug 1935 (Folder 2, Folder 3-R-13)
  - Dinwiddie - Darvilles- Addition, July 1935 (Folder 2, Folder 3-R-13)
  - Dinwiddie - Sunnyside- Addition, June 194- (Folder 2, Folder 3-R-13)
  - Essex - Auditorium (Lloyds High School), May 193- (Folder 2, Folder 3-R-17)
  - Essex - Tappahannock, Oct 193- (Folder 2, Folder 3-R-16)
  - Essex - Tappahannock High School- Lunch Room, Aug 194- (Folder 2, Folder 3-R-16)
  - Fairfax - Odricks, March 194- (Folder 2, Folder 4-L-15)
  - Fairfax - West End- Addition, June 193- (Folder 2, Folder 4-L-16)
  - Fairfax - West End- Addition, Oct 1927 (Folder 2, Folder 4-L-16)
  - Fairfax - West End, June 1925 (Folder 2, Folder 4-L-16)
  - Fairfax - Floris Elementary - Septic Tank, July 1925 (Folder 2, Folder 4-L-7)
  - Fairfax - Floris Elementary Toilets, Feb 1933 (Folder 2, Folder 4-L-7)
  - Fairfax - Floris Elementary- Addition, Aug 1935 (Folder 2, Folder 4-L-7)
  - Fairfax - Greenbrier, Dec 1943 (Folder 2, Folder 4-L-9)
  - Fairfax - Elementary- Alteration & Addition, Aug 1945 (Folder 2, Folder 4-L-9)
  - Fairfax - Madison, July 1945 (Folder 2, Folder 4-L-13)
  - Fairfax - McLean High School, Aug 192- (Folder 2, Folder 4-L-13)
  - Fairfax - McLean High School - Proposed Alterations, Feb 194- (Folder 2, Folder 4-L-13)
  - Fairfax - Baileys Elementary Proposed Alt., Jan 194- (Folder 2, Folder 4-L-2)
  - Fluvanna - Carysbrook Training (S.C. Abrams), May 1936 (Folder 3, Folder 4-R-3)
  - Fluvanna - Carysbrook High School, Jan 1934 (Folder 3, Folder 4-R-3)
  - Fluvanna - Palmyra Elementary, June 1936 (Folder 3, Folder 4-R-4)
  - Franklin - Henry- Addition, March 1940 (Folder 3, Folder 4-R-6)
  - Franklin - Boonsmill- Addition, June 1931 (Folder 3, Folder 4-R-5)
  - Franklin - Ferrum Elementary, June 1940 (Folder 3, Folder 4-R-7)
  - Franklin - Snow Creek- Addition, July 1937 (Folder 3, Folder 4-R-6)
  - Franklin - Brown Colored- Addition, Aug 1935 (Folder 3, Folder 4-R-5)
  - Franklin - Burnt Chimney- Addition, Aug 1935 (Folder 3, Folder 4-R-5)
  - Franklin - Glademill- Addition, Aug 1935 (Folder 3, Folder 4-R-5)
  - Fredrick - Rich Creek, Sept 1935 (Folder 3, Folder 4-R-16)
  - Fredrick - Narrows High School- Gymnasium Addition, April 193- (Folder 3, Folder 4-R-13)
  - Fredrick - Newport, May 1932 (Folder 3, Folder 4-R-14)
  - Fredrick - Narrows High School, June 193- (Folder 3, Folder 4-R-13)
  - Fredrick - Big Stony Creek, June 193- (Folder 3, Folder 4-R-12)
  - Fredrick - Glen Lyn, Aug 1926 (Folder 3, Folder 4-R-11)
  - Fredrick - Pembroke- Alterations, Oct 1930 (Folder 3, Folder 4-R-10)
  - Fredrick - Pearisburg School- Shop Addition, Dec 1940 (Folder 3, Folder 4-R-10)
  - Fredrick - Eggleston, Feb 1934 (Folder 3, Folder 4-R-15)
  - Fredrick - Clearbrook, Dec 1934 (Folder 3, Folder 4-R-9)
  - Fredrick - Gainesboro, June 1940 (Folder 3, Folder 4-R-9)
  - Fredrick - Gore (Folder 3, Folder 4-R-8)
  - Fredrick - Winchester- Temporary School, n.d. (Folder 3, Folder 4-R-8)
  - Fredrick - Stevens City (Folder 3, Folder 4-R-8)
  - Fredrick - Pembroke- Addition, June 193- (Folder 3, Folder 4-R-10)
  - Fredrick - Narrows High School- Athletic Field House, Oct 1932 (Folder 3, Folder 4-R-13)
  - Giles - Pembroke, July 1925 (Folder 3, Folder 4-R-10)
  - Gloucester - Gymnasium & High School (Miscellaneous), 1936 (Folder 3, Folder 5-L-1)
  - Gloucester - Botetourt High School (Folder 3, Folder 5-L-1)
  - Goochland - Goochland High School, Dec 1933 (Folder 3, Folder 5-L-2)
  - Goochland - Goochland High School - Garage, Dec 1940 (Folder 3, Folder 5-L-2)
  - Goochland - Sandyhook- Addition, July 1924 (Folder 3, Folder 5-L-2)
  - Goochland - Goochland Training School, Dec 1933 (Folder 3, Folder 5-L-3)
  - Grayson - Popular Grove, July 1930 (Folder 3, Folder 5-L-5)
  - Grayson - Independence - Auditorium, Dec. 1935 (Folder 3, Folder 5-L-7)
  - Grayson - Elk Creek - Vocational Shop Addition, March 1944 (Folder 3, Folder 5-L-6)
  - Grayson - Independence Combination, July 1935 (Folder 3, Folder 5-L-7)
  - Grayson - Elk Creek Elementary, June 1935 (Folder 3, Folder 5-L-6)
  - Grayson - White Top Gap- Addition, Sept 1940 (Folder 3, Folder 5-L-5)
  - Grayson - Bridal Creek- Addition, June 1935 (Folder 3, Folder 5-L-5)
  - Greene - Ruckersville- Addition, Feb 1941 (Folder 3, Folder 5-L-8)
  - Greene - Stanardsville- Addition, May 1934 (Folder 3, Folder 5-L-8)
  - Greene - Dyke, June 1938 (Folder 3, Folder 5-L-8)
  - Greensville - South Emporia Training, May 1929 (Folder 3, Folder 5-L-9)
  - Greensville - Three Room School, May 1932 (Folder 3, Folder 5-L-9)
  - Halifax - Turbville, May 1926 (Folder 3, Folder 5-L-12)
  - Halifax - Vocational Shop, Feb 1939 (Folder 3, Folder 5-L-12)
  - Halifax - Volens, March 1939 (Folder 3, Folder 5-L-13)
  - Hanover - Present Agricultural & Home Economics Building, Feb 1927 (Folder 3, Folder 5-L-15)
  - Hanover - Mechanicsville- Present School No. 1, Feb 1927 (Folder 3, Folder 5-L-15)
  - Hanover - Henry Clay High School- Vocational Shop Addition, July 1944 (Folder 3, Folder 5-L-14)
  - Hanover - Atlee- Present High School, Feb 1927 (Folder 3, Folder 5-L-15)
  - Hanover - Four Room School, Nov 1924 (Folder 3, Folder 5-L-14)
  - Hanover - Hanover Union, July 1932 (Folder 3, Folder 5-L-14)
  - Hanover - Oak Lawn- Present High School, Feb 1927 (Folder 3, Folder 5-L-15)
  - Henry - Axton Elementary, Aug 1926 (Folder 3, Folder 5-R-11)
  - Henry - Bassett Elementary, Jan 1937 (Folder 3, Folder 5-R-13)
  - Henry - Bassett High School, July 1928 (Folder 3, Folder 5-R-13)
  - Henry - Bassett High School, June 192- (Folder 3, Folder 5-R-13)
  - Henry - Bassett High School, Sept 192- (Folder 3, Folder 5-R-13)
  - Henry - Spencer Penn Elementary, July 1942 (Folder 3, Folder 5-R-12)
  - Henry - Spencer Penn Elementary, Sept 1926 (Folder 3, Folder 5-R-12)
  - Henry - Axton, June 1935 (Folder 3, Folder 5-R-11)
  - Henry - Martinsville, July 193- (Folder 3, Folder 5-R-10)
  - Henry - Sanville- Addition, Sept 1938 (Folder 3, Folder 5-R-9)
  - Henry - Fielday High School, Jan 194- (Folder 3, Folder 5-R-8)
  - Henry - Fielday High School, June 192- (Folder 3, Folder 5-R-8)
  - Henry - Ridgeway- Vocational Building, June 193- (Folder 3, Folder 5-R-7)
  - Henry - Ridgeway Elementary- Addition, July 193- (Folder 3, Folder 5-R-7)
  - Henry - Ridgeway Elementary, June 1928 (Folder 3, Folder 5-R-7)
  - Henry - Axton- Addition, March 194- (Folder 3, Folder 5-R-11)
  - Isle of Wight - Windsor- Addition, June 1933 (Folder 4, Folder 6-L-2)
  - Isle of Wight - Smithfield High School- Lunch Room, May 1945 (Folder 4, Folder 6-L-3)
  - Isle of Wight - Smithfield Training- Addition, May 1945 (Folder 4, Folder 6-L-4)
  - Isle of Wight - Smithfield Training- Addition, May 1941 (Folder 4, Folder 6-L-4)
  - Isle of Wight - Isle of Wight Training, July 1935 (Folder 4, Folder 6-L-4)
  - Isle of Wight - Carrsville- Addition, June 1935 (Folder 4, Folder 6-L-1)
  - Isle of Wight - Carrsville (6 Room), May 1923 (Folder 4, Folder 6-L-1)
  - Isle of Wight - Smithfield, June 193- (Folder 4, Folder 6-L-3)
  - Isle of Wight - Agricultural Building Carrsville, July 1926 (Folder 4, Folder 6-L-1)
  - King & Queen - Marriott & Shanghai, Aug 1937 (Folder 4, Folder 6-L-6)
  - King George - King George C. H.- Addition, Jan 192- (Folder 4, Folder 6-L-5)
  - King George - King George C. H.- Addition, July 1933 (Folder 4, Folder 6-L-5)
  - King George - King George High School, Oct. 1938 (Folder 4, Folder 6-L-5)
  - King George - King George High School- Addition, March 194- (Folder 4, Folder 6-L-5)
  - Lancaster - Lively, May 1927 (Folder 4, Folder 6-L-8)
  - Lancaster - Addition Lively, Feb 1934 (Folder 4, Folder 6-L-8)
  - Lancaster - Kilmarnock, Oct 1938 (Folder 4, Folder 6-L-8)
  - Lee - St. Charles- Alterations & Additions, June 1936 (Folder 4, Folder 6-L-12)
  - Lee - Thomas Walker High School - Auditorium - Gymnasium, Feb 1939 (Folder 4, Folder 6-L-17)
  - Lee - Keokee- Alterations, Oct 1938 (Folder 4, Folder 6-L-16)
  - Lee - Keokee, Feb 1941 (Folder 4, Folder 6-L-16)
  - Lee - Dryden (Folder 4, Folder 6-L-15)
  - Lee - Thomas Walker High School, Feb 1939 (Folder 4, Folder 6-L-17)
  - Lee - Blackwater, Jan 1930 (Folder 4, Folder 6-L-14)
  - Lee - Jonesville Gymnasium, Dec 1933 (Folder 4, Folder 6-L-13)
  - Lee - Jonesville, Oct 1929 (Folder 4, Folder 6-L-13)
  - Lee - St. Charles, Nov 1926 (Folder 4, Folder 6-L-12)
  - Lee - Pennington Gap Colored, May 1940 (Folder 4, Folder 6-L-11)
  - Lee - Pennington Gap, Aug 192- (Folder 4, Folder 6-L-11)
  - Lee - Rose Hill- Repairs, July 192- (Folder 4, Folder 6-L-10)
  - Lee - Flatwoods, Aug 1936 (Folder 4, Folder 6-L-10)
  - Lee - Elk Knob- Addition, June 192- (Folder 4, Folder 6-L-10)
  - Lee - Stickleyville- Addition, June 192- (Folder 4, Folder 6-L-10)
  - Lee - Stone - Standard One Room School, Aug 1924 (Folder 4, Folder 6-L-10)
  - Lee - St. Charles- Addition, July 1928 (Folder 4, Folder 6-L-12)
  - Lee - Blackwood- Addition, May 1936 (Folder 4, Folder 6-L-14)
  - Loudoun - Ashburn Elementary, July 194- (Folder 4, Folder 6-R-9)
  - Loudoun - Middleburg Elementary - Shop, March 19-- (Folder 4, Folder 6-R-5)
  - Loudoun - Luckettsville, June 19-- (Folder 4, Folder 6-R-5)
  - Loudoun - Aldie, March 19-- (Folder 4, Folder 6-R-6)
  - Loudoun - Arcola, Aug 193- (Folder 4, Folder 6-R-6)
  - Loudoun - Ashburn - Toilet Addition, Nov 192- (Folder 4, Folder 6-R-7)
  - Loudoun - Middleburg, June 19-- (Folder 4, Folder 6-R-5)
  - Loudoun - Leesburg Training, Jan 194- (Folder 4, Folder 6-R-8)
  - Loudoun - Mountville, May 193- (Folder 4, Folder 6-R-6)
  - Loudoun - Hillsboro - Toilet Addition, May 193- (Folder 4, Folder 6-R-7)
  - Loudoun - Purcellville- Addition, April 1937 (Folder 4, Folder 6-R-4)
  - Loudoun - Addition Lovettsville, Jan 1927 (Folder 4, Folder 6-R-3)
  - Loudoun - Lovettsville, Aug 194- (Folder 4, Folder 6-R-3)
  - Loudoun - Shop, May 1930 (Folder 4, Folder 6-R-2)
  - Loudoun - Hillsboro - Auditorium, April 1929 (Folder 4, Folder 6-R-2)
  - Loudoun - Waterford - Auditorium, April 1927 (Folder 4, Folder 6-R-2)
  - Loudoun - Lincoln- Two Room Addition, Dec 1940 (Folder 4, Folder 6-R-1)
  - Loudoun - Lincoln- Addition, Aug 1933 (Folder 4, Folder 6-R-1)
  - Loudoun - Lincoln, July 1926 (Folder 4, Folder 6-R-1)
  - Loudoun - Leesburg High School- Addition, Jan 193- (Folder 4, Folder 6-R-7)
  - Loudoun - Purcellville, June 1928 (Folder 4, Folder 6-R-4)
  - Louisa - Louisa High School- Toilet Additions, Aug 192- (Folder 4, Folder 6-R-11)
  - Louisa - Mineral Grade School, 1960 (Folder 4, Folder 6-R-12)
  - Louisa - Mineral High School, May 192- (Folder 4, Folder 6-R-12)
  - Louisa - Centerville - Colored, Nov 193- (Folder 4, Folder 6-R-11)
  - Louisa - Home Economics Cottage, Oct. 193- (Folder 4, Folder 6-R-10)
  - Louisa - Apple Grove, Feb 1930 (Folder 4, Folder 6-R-10)
  - Louisa - Mineral- Addition, June 1923 (Folder 4, Folder 6-R-12)
  - Louisa - Louisa High School, June 192- (Folder 4, Folder 6-R-11)
  - Lunenburg - Victoria- Two Room School, July 1939 (Folder 4, Folder 6-R-14)
  - Lunenburg - Kenbridge, May 194- (Folder 4, Folder 6-R-15)
  - Lunenburg - Agricultural Building - Training School, July 1927 (Folder 4, Folder 6-R-15)
  - Lunenburg - Victoria-Additions, Jan 1934 (Folder 4, Folder 6-R-14)
  - Lunenburg - Victoria- Alterations, May 192- (Folder 4, Folder 6-R-14)
  - Lunenburg - Rehobath District School, April 192- (Folder 4, Folder 6-R-13)
  - Lunenburg - Home Economics Cottage - Training-Additions, April 194- (Folder 4, Folder 6-R-15)
  - Madison - School For Madison County, Oct 1929 (Folder 4, Folder 6-R-16)
  - Madison - Madison, Dec 1937 (Folder 4, Folder 6-R-16)
  - Madison - Madison County Colored School, June 1935 (Folder 4, Folder 6-R-17)
  - Madison - Criglersville- Addition, Sept 1940 (Folder 4, Folder 6-R-17)
  - Mathews - Lee Jackson, March 1933 (Folder 5, Folder 7-L-1)
  - Mathews - New Point- Addition, June 1924 (Folder 5, Folder 7-L-1)
  - Mecklenburg - La Crosse- Addition, Feb 1939 (Folder 5, Folder 7-L-6)
  - Mecklenburg - School For South Hill, June 1932 (Folder 5, Folder 7-L-2)
  - Mecklenburg - Colored Shop- Addition, April 1940 (Folder 5, Folder 7-L-2)
  - Mecklenburg - Chase City- Addition, June 1923 (Folder 5, Folder 7-L-3)
  - Mecklenburg - School for Chase City, June 1929 (Folder 5, Folder 7-L-3)
  - Mecklenburg - Chase City- Addition, April 1938 (Folder 5, Folder 7-L-3)
  - Mecklenburg - Clarksville, July 1934 (Folder 5, Folder 7-L-4)
  - Mecklenburg - Clarksville Training- Home Economics Cottage, April 1940 (Folder 5, Folder 7-L-4)
  - Mecklenburg - Union Level - 4 Room School, June 1925 (Folder 5, Folder 7-L-5)
  - Mecklenburg - La Crosse- Addition, May 1929 (Folder 5, Folder 7-L-6)
  - Mecklenburg - South Hill -Standard 8 Room School, Dec 1922 (Folder 5, Folder 7-L-2)
  - Middlesex - County Training - (Plot Plan), July 1938 (Folder 5, Folder 7-L-8)
  - Middlesex - Urbanna- Toilet Addition, March 1936 (Folder 5, Folder 7-L-8)
  - Middlesex - Home Economics Extension, Aug 1935 (Folder 5, Folder 7-L-8)
  - Middlesex - Sryinga, Aug 1935 (Folder 5, Folder 7-L-8)
  - Middlesex - Unionville- Addition, May 1923 (Folder 5, Folder 7-L-7)
  - Middlesex - School For Churchview, May 1925 (Folder 5, Folder 7-L-7)
  - Montgomery - Standard One Teacher School, Sept 1930 (Folder 5, Folder 7-L-9)
  - Montgomery - School For Walton, May 1931 (Folder 5, Folder 7-L-9)
  - Montgomery - Riner Agricultural Shop- Addition, April 1943 (Folder 5, Folder 7-L-9)
  - Montgomery - Adams House- Alterations & Additions, Aug 1935 (Folder 5, Folder 7-L-9)
  - Nansemond - Shipman Training- Alterations & Additions, Feb 1946 (Folder 5, Folder 7-L-11)
  - Nansemond - Chukatuck- Addition, April 1938 (Folder 5, Folder 7-L-11)
  - Nansemond - Kings Fork - 4 Room High School & Auditorium, June 1926 (Folder 5, Folder 7-L-10)
  - Nansemond - Suffolk Training, Oct 1938 (Folder 5, Folder 7-L-12)
  - Nelson - Lovington High School- Addition, July 1936 (Folder 5, Folder 7-L-13)
  - Nelson - Fleetwood High School- Addition, Aug 1936 (Folder 5, Folder 7-L-13)
  - Nelson - Rockfish District, Aug 1938 (Folder 5, Folder 7-L-14)
  - Nelson - Rockfish District- Addition, Aug 1938 (Folder 5, Folder 7-L-14)
  - New Kent - School For New Kent, Oct 1929 (Folder 5, Folder 7-L-15)
  - New Kent - New Kent- Addition, Aug 1934 (Folder 5, Folder 7-L-15)
  - New Kent - School For Quinton, April 193- (Folder 5, Folder 7-L-15)
  - Northampton - School For Cape Charles, June 1928 (Folder 5, Folder 7-L-18)